<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>theodorton.github.io</title>
    <link>https://theodorton.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on theodorton.github.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 18:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://theodorton.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>TIL: February 2020</title>
      <link>https://theodorton.github.io/til-february-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theodorton.github.io/til-february-2020/</guid>
      <description>I started last month setting up a Linux server at home that I use for remote VS Code work. A lot of learning followed as I&amp;rsquo;ve never use Linux outside a server environment, except for some short periods of fiddling with Pop!_OS. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably write up a longer article later, but for now the majority of my TILs the past month has been related to that project.
Linux  You can run simple GUI applications like xeyes and git gui over SSH using X11 and XQuartz How to run VSCode remotely on a linux server with VS Code Remote/SSH extension You can setup default ports to forward on a remote VSCode workspace  ̂ + ⎇ + T  toggles the Terminal panel in VSCode tmux integrates nicely with iterm2 Use tmux select-layout even-vertical to resize panes evenly tmux -CC starts in Control mode (and disables eCho) How to fix iTerm 2 so it uses Natural Text Editing preset (via @sobstel) neofetch - the CLI equivalent to &amp;ldquo;About my computer&amp;rdquo; You can restrict which commands that can be run over SSH in authorized_keys How to change hostname on ubuntu  Productivity/development  ActiveRecord has a comment keyword argument for add_column that works with postgres How to fix HMR in expo react-navigation Assign env vars to constants and use stub_const over mocking env vars in tests git checkout - navigates back to your previously checked out branch similar to cd - @ in slack shows recent activity (via @jennysjogren) Heroku supports multiple credentials for their Postgres databases  Random  The brain has 80 billion neurons&amp;hellip; How to remove stearin stains from clothes: use a paper towel and an iron BTDTBTTS; Been There Done That Bought The T-Shirt Variomatic transmission; drives as fast in reverse  Stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered but didn&amp;rsquo;t have time to pursue yet  grasshopper / rhino parametric cad Geonames.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>TIL: January 2020</title>
      <link>https://theodorton.github.io/til-january-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 06:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theodorton.github.io/til-january-2020/</guid>
      <description>Back in August 2018 I started the habit of writing down stuff I learn. I had come across a lot of TIL posts on reddit, which inspired me to start building a library of personal knowledge.
Since then I&amp;rsquo;ve had some months on and off, some more documented than others. I keep a TIL list in my Workflowy that I like to refer back to.
This year I&amp;rsquo;d like to become better at taking notes of the random facts, computer tricks and techniques I run across.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>7DRL</title>
      <link>https://theodorton.github.io/7drl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theodorton.github.io/7drl/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr My friend and I made a roguelike named Skyspire. It&amp;rsquo;s our first roguelike, and first game in a long while. You can find the code on Github.
A week ago I decided to do a 7DRL Challenge. I&amp;rsquo;ve been tinkering with different game engines since middle school, but I tend to start projects without finishing. I read about the 7DRL concept some time last year, and I figured it seemed like a good idea to actually get to something playable.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
